# SHAMIM KHALED

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: i.amkhaled89@gmail.com Phone: +8801624462494

GitHub: www.github.com/shamimkhaled Address: 128/3, Kawran Bazar, Dhaka-1215

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shamim-khaled-809896223/

#### **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic developer with over 1 years of experience working as frontend and backend developer.

Solid experience with Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery and integrating, developing REST/APIs

Ability to rapidly learn and integrate new acquisitions to projects.

#### Areas of expertise:

Programming Language: Python, Java, JavaScript, C, C++, C#, PHP

Frameworks: Django, React JS

Web Developments: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5, JavaScript, and

WordPress.

Machine Learning and Deep Learning: Web Scraping, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Classification and Clustering, Predictive Model-

ling and Analysis, ML Algorithms, DL Algorithms

Database Design

Version Controlling systems (Git)

Development Environments: VS Code, PyCharm,

Jupyter Notebook, Colab

Database: MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Rana Motors, Baridhara, Dhaka **Web Developer**

Sept 2022 - Present

**Inventory Management System Website:** 

I have worked on a project that is a web-based application called the Inventory Management System of Rana Motors. This project is being worked on by me and a friend, with me as a front-end and back-end developer and my friend as a backend developer and maintained the AWS server. I'm working on this project as the front-end and back-end developer and Django admin panel maintainer. coded websites using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5, JavaScript, and the Python Django web framework along with SQL, which is deployed on an AWS server using an EC2 instance.

Web: http://18.144.62.238:8000/

eNexusMart Website: In this project, we used a CodeCanyon template to build this eNexusMart e-commerce website. We maintenance the website is the process of keeping a website current, functional, and functioning smoothly as well as adding and updating products, designing banners and logos, and performing activities. Coded websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery and PHP Laravel framework. Website: http://enexusmart.com

# Auto Pac, Kawran Bazar, Dhaka

Feb 2019 - Jan 2021

# Website Manager

- Responsible for maintaining Auto Pac websites and overseeing the functionality of the website, evaluating and managing website performance, facilitating hosting and server management; and developing, maintaining, and updating website content. Web: <a href="http://autopacbd.com/">http://autopacbd.com/</a>
- And also executed on daily data entry responsibilities for a fast-paced company machinery sales quotation.
- Performed data entry for all quotations and mailings and used MS Word daily, including Excel.

# **CLIENTS PROJECTS**

## **Carom Board 2D Game in Unity**

Jan 2023 - Currently work on

I'm currently working on a Carom 2D game project as a Unity Game Developer, and this project is being worked on by me and my friend, with me as a game UI designer and script developer and my friend as a Unity Game UI Designer, and my friend helps me write code and logic in script. My responsibility is to implement the core functionality of the game, including the physics and gameplay mechanics. They work closely with the Unity engine, writing scripts and logic to bring the game to life. And my friends focus on creating visually appealing and user-friendly interfaces for the game. They work alongside the Unity game developer, contributing to the design of the game's user interface elements and ensuring a seamless user experience.

#### **MERN Stack Pet Shop Application**

## May 2023 - Currently work on

This project, which comprises MongoDB, Express JS, ReactJS, and NodeJS, was used to create a full-stack pet shop application. The front-end is maintained by ReactJS, while the backend is supported by NodeJS and Express JS. The front-end and back-end communicate via a REST API, allowing for the independent development of both the front-end and back-end components of the application. Pet Shop is a MERN stack application meant to digitize the process of purchasing and selling pets as well as providing pet services. The aim of the application is to provide a platform for pet enthusiasts all over the world to connect and buy a range of pets, pet food, pet accessories, pet medicine, and pet services.

#### **Bangla Text to Speech using Deep Learning**

## May 2023 - Currently work on

The Bangla Text-to-Speech (TTS) project is an exciting deep learning endeavor aimed at developing a system capable of converting Bangla text into audio. This project leverages advanced techniques in deep learning to train a model that can understand and generate human-like speech in the Bengali language. The Bangla TTS dataset by bengali.ai contains approximately 2000 Bangla sentences and audio IDs. This dataset was collected from Bangladeshi Bengali speakers in bengali.ai. This project uses a Bangla text-to-speech (TTS) technique based on deep convolutional neural networks (CNN) without the use of any recurrent units. This Bengali text-to-speech model is a CNN-based architecture with an attention mechanism.

# **NOTEABLE PROJECTS**

- 1. Stock Market Prices Analysis and Prediction in ML (ARIMA, LSTM, PROPHET, and GRU Model)
- 2. Water Quality Factor Prediction in ML
- 3. Breast Cancer Prediction in ML
- 4. Image Classification with CNN
- 5. Emotion Speech Recognition in NLP
- 6. Movie Recommendation System
- 7. **Django Ecommerce** (Django, SQLite, HTML5, CSS3, Boostrap5)
- 8. **Simple Food App** (Django, SQLite, HTML5, CSS3, Boostrap5)
- 9. **Django Rest Framework Project** (Django, SQLite, HTML5, CSS, Boostrap5)
- 10. CryptoX Web App in React JS (React JS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS Library Chakra-UI, Boostrap5)
- 11. Techux React JS Web App (React JS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Boostrap5)
- 12. **Simple News App in React JS** (React JS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Boostrap5)
- 13. **Super Shop Billing System in JavaFX** (JavaFX, Java, Scene Builder)
- 14. **Student Management System Java Swing** (Java Swing, Java)

#### **EDUCATION**

North South University, Bangladesh	2018 - 2022
B.Sc Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering	
BAF Shaheen College PKP, Tangail	2015 - 2017
Higher Secondary Certificate, Science Group	
BAF Shaheen College PKP, Tangail	2013 - 2015
Secondary School Certificate, Science Group	